Guide to the Ralph Rydholm papers, 1936-2014 and undated RL.11279
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Ralph Rydholm papers
1936-2014 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Rydholm, Ralph William, 1937-2014
RL.11279
36.0 Linear Feet
Advertising executive who worked in a number of agencies in Chicago and New York. Collection spans 1936-2014 and includes correspondence, proofs and tear sheets, sketches and cartoons, copy scripts, research reports and other printed materials, photographs and slides, audiovisual materials in multiple formats (audio and video cassettes, 16mm and 35mm film and audio reels, dvds and phono discs) and other materials that document Rydholm's career in advertising agencies in Chicago and New York including BBDO, E.H. Weiss, EURO RSCG, J. Walter Thompson (JWT), Post Keyes Gardner, Tatham-Laird, Ted Bates, and Young & Rubicam. Collection also documents Rydholm's military service with the U.S. Air Force and participation in some War Production Board youth activities during World War II, as well as his tenure as President of the American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA). Companies represented include Alberto-Culver, American Bar Association, Chicago Museum of Sports, Chicago Public Education Fund, Executive Service Corps, Hoover vacuum cleaners, and Northwestern University. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Personal and Professional Files; Print Materials; Artifacts and Memorabilia; and Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Born 1937, Chicago, Ill.; BA Northwestern University 1958; U.S. Air Force 1958-1959; Air Force Reserve 1959-1965; Young & Rubicam 1960-1963; Post Keyes Gardner 1963; E.H. Weiss agency 1963-1965 (copywriter); BBDO 1965-1966 (Copy Supervisor); 1966-1985 JWT Chicago (Creative Supervisor 1966-1969, Vice President and Creative Director 1969-1980, Board of Directors 1980, resigned 1985); Harvard Advanced Management Program 1982; 1986 Ted Bates Advertising (Chief Creative Officer); 1987-1998 Tatham-Laird and Kudner--later Euro RSCG Tatham (Chief Creative Officer, CEO); 1991 Adweek Advertising Executive of the Year; 1999 JWT Chicago (consultant); 2014 died, Chicago.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials remain closed to researchers until use copies can be produced.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Ralph Rydholm papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Bates Worldwide Inc. records; Garrett Orr papers; J. Walter Thompson Company Advertising Vertical Files; J. Walter Thompson Company Account Files; J. Walter Thompson Company Small Accessions; J. Walter Thompson Company World War II Advertising Collection; War Effort Mobilization Campaigns Poster Collection.
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1936-2014 and includes correspondence, proofs and tear sheets, sketches and cartoons, copy scripts, research reports and other printed materials, photographs and slides, audiovisual materials in multiple formats (audio and video cassettes, 16mm and 35mm film and audio reels, dvds and phono discs) and other materials that document Rydholm's career in advertising agencies in Chicago and New York including BBDO, E.H. Weiss, EURO RSCG, J. Walter Thompson (JWT), Post Keyes Gardner, Tatham-Laird, Ted Bates, and Young & Rubicam. Collection also documents Rydholm's military service with the U.S. Air Force and participation in some War Production Board youth activities during World War II, as well as his tenure as President of the American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA). Companies represented include Alberto-Culver, American Bar Association, Chicago Museum of Sports, Chicago Public Education Fund, Executive Service Corps, Hoover vacuum cleaners, and Northwestern University. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Separated Materials
Materials separated from this collection and cataloged individually may be accessed by searching the Duke University Libraries website: here
Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising; Advertising agencies; Chicago (Ill.) -- Commerce; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company; American Bar Association; Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborn, Inc.; Hoover Company; Northwestern University (Evanston, Ill.); Ted Bates Advertising; United States. Air Force; Young & Rubicam
- Personal and Professional Files, 1945-2014 and undated; 1
  - General Files, 1945-2014 and undated; 1
    - Awards, certificates, 1956-2003 (Box 1)
    - Awards, certificates, 1969-1990 (Box OV1)
    - Awards, certificates, 1975-2014 (Box OV8)
    - Awards--Executive Service Corps plaque, 2010 (Box OV7)
    - Awards--Cannes Silver Lion, 1973 (Box OV6)
    - Awards--New York Times, McCall's Best Man in Advertising, 1992 (Box OV6)
    - Awards--Outdoor Advertising Workshop plaque, 1969 (Box 23)
    - Awards--Wall Street Journal plaque, 1994 (Box OV8)
    - Biographical, CVs, etc., undated (Box 1)
    - "Building inspiration" quote, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Change of command ceremony, USS John F. Kennedy, CV-67 (includes correspondence with Rear Admiral Gary Wheatley, USN), 1983-1986 (Box 1)
    - Childhood, 1945-1954; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Childhood--Drawing to Auntie Helen, undated (Box OV6)
    - Childhood--War Production Board Paper Trooper Award, 1945 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 1)
    - Doyle Spell 60th birthday, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Fred Stenger (film director), clippings and obituary, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
    - Harvard Advanced Management Program, 1982-1993; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Humorous posters, undated (Box OV5)
    - Interview release, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Leo Burnett--Allstate model release, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Military service (U.S. Air Force), 1959; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous copy, undated (Box 2)
    - NARC (National Advertising Review Council), 1999 (Box 2)
    - Northwestern University, 1958-2003; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Poems and other writings, undated (Box 2)
    - R2 Consulting stationery, undated (Box 2)
    - Rydholm memorials and obituary, 2014 (Box 2)
    - Rydholm tributes, 1996-2002 (Box OV5)
    - Sketches and caricatures, undated (Box 2)
    - Sketches and caricatures, undated (Box OV1)
    - Sketches and caricatures, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      "Fresh Eggs"; "Flying Lessons"; Happy Birthday Ralph
    - Sketches and caricatures, undated (Box OV5)
    - Sketches and caricatures--"Nobody Does It Like You" art by Sonny Veneracion, 1998 (Box OV6)
    - Sketches and caricatures--Painting "That Madcap Duo Is At It Again", 1984 (Box OV9)
    - Sketches and caricatures--Sawgrass Tournament Players Club: Ralph "100 and Counting" Rydholm, 1995 (Box OV6)
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies), 1987-2000 and undated; 2
    - Advertising Agency of the Future, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Articles and clippings, 1990-1997; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Beijing conference, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Charlotte Beers address, 1987 (Box 2)
    - John O'Toole address, 1989 (Box 2)
    - John O'Toole--Road to Commoditization, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Leonard Matthews, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
    - Presentations, 1987-1989 (Box 2)
    - What the AAAA Does, undated (Box 2)
  - BBDO (Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborne), 1965-1987; 3
    - Henninger Beer, undated (Box OV3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1987 (Box 3)
    - Newsletters, 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Clients/Activities, 1969-2012 and undated; 4
    - 37th Outdoor Advertising Competition (Rydholm was judge), 1969 (Box 3)
    - ABA Commission on the American Jury, 2004-2005; 7 folders (Box 3)
    - Advertising and Ethics Forum, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Agency Management Group, 1999 (Box 4)
    - American Scandinavian Council, 1994-1999; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Chicago Bears, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Chicago Museum of Sports, 1999-2001; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Chicago Museum of Sports, 1999 (Box OV3)
    - Chicago Public Education Fund, 1999-2001; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - City of Chicago "Principal for a Day", 1998 (Box 4)
    - CSSR (Consortium on Chicago School Research), 2000-2001 (Box 5)
    - Executive Service Corps, 2003-2012; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Executive Service Corps--Actors' Gymnasium, 2008 (Box 5)
    - Executive Service Corps--Pegasus Players, 2006-2007 (Box 5)
    - Fingerweights, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Foulds, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Hayden-Stone copy, undated (Box 5)
    - Hedlund for Alderman, undated (Box OV6)
    - Home Team, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Horizon Cash Management (English and Italian), 2006-2010; 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Horizon Cash Management (English and Italian), 2007-2010 (Box OV3)
    - MAX (Managing Advertising Expenditures) Conference, 1998 (Box 5)
    - Newberry Library, 1992, 2007 (Box 5)
    - Northwestern University brand initiative, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Northwestern University brand initiative (Box 6)
    - Photonails (Steve Durchslag) (Box 6)
  - E.H. Weiss, 1964-1965 and undated; 5
    - American National Bank script, 1964 (Box 6)
    - Awrey baked goods, Corina cigars, General American Transportation, Kings Men, 1964-1965 (Box OV3)
    - Carling Red Cap, undated (Box 6)
    - General American Transportation Corporation (GATX), 1964-1965 (Box 6)
    - King's Men, 1964 (Box 6)
    - Mac Churchill, undated (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous creative [Awrey Bakeries, Brown & Williamson (Biltmore, Carina Lark cigars), General American Transportation, King's Men, Inland Steel, Orange Crush, Serta], 1964 and undated; 2 folders (Box OV4)
  - JWT (J. Walter Thompson Company), 1964-2000 and undated; 6
    - 120th anniversary print of Mr. Thompson, 1984 (Box 6)
    - Alberto-Culver, 1966 (Box OV3)
    - Alberto-Culver, 1966 (Box OV4)
    - Analysis if AdTrieval and 333, 2000 (Box 6)
    - Atlanta Office, 1980 (Box 6)
    - Chicago Tribune, Sears creative, 1968-1972 (Box OV4)
    - Children's Hour presentation, undated (Box 6)
    - Clients, Client Relations and Client Service (Denis Lanigan), 1978 (Box 6)
    - Clippings, 1967-1999; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1969-1992 and undated; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1969-1992 and undated; 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Cynthia Swank (JWT Archivist)--Some Basic Roots of the J. Walter Thompson Company, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Ford Taurus spots, 1985 (Box 7)
    - FTC meetings on cable television advertising, 1980 (Box 7)
    - Gillette, Holiday Spas, 1973-1975 (Box OV3)
    - Guide to Written Communications, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Henry M. Goodman Furniture Stores, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Holiday Spas, KenL Ration, Simoniz newsprint, 1967-1975 (Box OV3)
    - J. Walter Ralph house ad, Knoblauch feature, Sears, 1971 and undated (Box OV6)
    - KenL Ration, Pan Am, 1967-1969 (Box OV3)
    - Hoover, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Hoover--Brandscape results, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Hoover--Maytag annual report, 1998 (Box 7)
    - Hoover--Presentation, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Is There a Crisis in Branding in the United States? (Joel Baumwoll), 1978 (Box 7)
    - JWT: Reputation and Reality (Arnold Grisman), 1978 (Box 7)
    - Leadership at JWT, undated (Box 7)
    - London Office--Crisis in Branding, 1978 (Box 7)
    - London Office--How People Use Advertising and How to Understand It (Judie Lannon), 1983 (Box 7)
    - London Office--T-Plan, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Managing a JWT Office for Performance and Profit: 2. Profit (E.G.A. Bathon), 1978 (Box 8)
    - Managing a JWT Office for Performance and Profit: 4. Product and Profit--You Can't Have One Without the Other (William E. Ross), 1978 (Box 8)
    - Mary Kuhnahblow "Enterprise" marketing plan, 1971 (Box 8)
    - Memo (was framed), Operating Committee, 1978 (Box 8)
    - New Business Review, 1978 (Box 8)
    - "New" Medium: Television in the 1980s (Marie Luisi), 1978 (Box 8)
    - Newsletter article on Simoniz "Submarine" commercial, 1967 (Box 8)
    - Parker Pen script, 1967 (Box 8)
    - Print advertisements (Sears, Uncle Ben's), 1970-1973 (Box 8)
    - Reshaping JWT for Future Needs and Opportunities (Denis Lanigan), 1978 (Box 8)
    - Ronco, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Schlitz--Fortune Magazine feature, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Sears (includes Allstate), 1968-1973 (Box OV3)
    - Sears radio copy, 1968 (Box 8)
    - Troutbeck--Management effectiveness, 1983 (Box 8)
    - True Serv, 1998-1999 (Box 8)
    - Uncle Ben's, undated (Box OV3)
    - U.S. Playing Card Company, undated (Box 8)
    - U.S. Professionals Conference, 1979 (Box 8)
    - What JWT Stands For, undated (Box 8)
  - Post Keyes Gardner, 1964 and undated; 7
    - Breeze, Raleigh notes, undated (Box 8)
    - Burgermeister Beer, Italian Balm, 1963 (Box OV3)
    - San Francisco campaign creative rationale (Burgermeister Beer?), 1964 (Box 8)
  - Tatham (Includes Tatham-Laird & Kudner, EURO RSCG Tatham), 1976-1998 and undated; 8
    - Agency history, 1996 (Box 8)
    - Agency information (binder), 1992-1993 (Box 8)
    - Agency philosophy notes, undated (Box 9)
    - Amati, 1991 (Box 9)
    - Ameritech presentation and second-line campaign, 1994 (Box 9)
    - Articles and clippings, 1987-1995; 6 folders (Box 9)
    - Articles and clippings, 1987-1995; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Audi, 1993 (Box 10)
    - Awards recaps, 1989-1991 (Box 10)
    - CEBA (Creative Excellence in Business Advertising) Awards, 1997 (Box 10)
    - Charlotte Beers, 1992-1993 (Box 10)
    - Charlotte Beers review of Chicago advertising, 1990 (Box 10)
    - Client lists, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Clio Awards, 1993 (Box 10)
    - Commercials lists, 1993-1996 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1987-1992; 4 folders (Box 10)
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1993-1999; 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Correspondence (Binders), 1992-1993; 5 folders (Box 11)
    - Correspondence (Binders), 1993-1994; 3 folders (Box 12)
    - C.R. Standen memo on Tatham philosophy, 1979 (Box 12)
    - Dean Foods, undated (Box OV4)
    - Gallo, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Hardee's, 1993; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Illinois Bell "We're All Connected," undated (Box 12)
    - Illinois State Lottery, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Job descriptions, 1976-1977 (Box 12)
    - John Deere, 1989 (Box 12)
    - Life at Tatham, anniversary issue, 1996 (Box 12)
    - Lightbulb--Tilting Brand Preference, undated (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous creative [Brown & Williamson (Capri, Misty), Coors Cutter, Everen Securities, Head & Shoulders, Hoover, Huffy, Kemper, Mr. Clean, Old Spice, One A Day, Vidal Sassoon[, 1994-1996 (Box OV3)
    - New business, 1992 (Box 13)
    - Nissan, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Peoplebook, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Print advertisements [Brown & Williamson (Capri, Misty), Hoover, Huffy, Kemper, Metamucil, Miles (One a Day, Flintstones vitamins)], 1994-1996 (Box 13)
    - Ralph's going away party, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Tatham Topics, 1995-1997 (Box 13)
    - We're All Connected--Case study for speeches, undated (Box 13)
    - What Is a Brand, undated (Box 13)
    - William Claggett (Ralston Purina) presentation on new business, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Wolverine Worldwide, 1993-1996 (Box 13)
  - Ted Bates, 1982-1987; 9
    - About Ted Bates, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Bates and Saatchi: A Global Family (Larry Light), 1986 (Box 13)
    - Clippings, 1985-1987; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Competitive marketing strategy, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1986-1987; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Five Principles of Mars, 1983 (Box 13)
    - Heineken storyboard, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 14)
    - Primetime network schedule, 1985 (Box 14)
    - Saatchi--Preparing the Advertising Brief, 1986 (Box 14)
    - The Bates Book, 1982 (Box 14)
    - The USP Agency, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Young & Rubicam, 1960-1964 and undated; 10
    - Allied creative, 1962 (Box 14)
    - American Bakeries (Taystee), 1961-1962; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - American Bakeries (Taystee), 1962 (Box OV6)
    - Armour, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
    - Baseball memos (humor), 1962 (Box 14)
    - Borden, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
    - Foulds, 1963 (Box 14)
    - Function of a Junior Merchandising Man, or (The Rise and _____ of RW Rydholm), circa 1960 (Box 14)
    - Hammond Organ, 1964 (Box 14)
    - Hammond Organ, 1962 (Box OV3)
    - Merchandising, 1960; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960 and undated (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous creative [Allied, American Bakeries (Taystee, Cook Book), Aurora bathroom tissue], 1962 (Box OV3)
    - Miscellaneous creative [Allied, American Bakeries (Taystee, D'Agostino), 1962; 2 folders (Box OV4)
    - Old Milwaukee, 1962 (Box 14)
  - Yearbooks and Scrapbooks, 1950-1998; 11
    - Austin High School, 1950-1954 (Box 15)
    - Northwestern University, 1956, 1958 (Box 16)
    - Scrapbooks--Blue, 1945-1973 (Box 17)
    - Scrapbooks--Ralph!, 1973-1998 (Box 17)
    - Scrapbooks--Red, 1963-1975 (Box 17)
    - Scrapbooks--White, 1960-1988 (Box 17)
  - Speeches and Presentations, 1970-2003 and undated; 12
    - AAAA client panel, 1997 (Box 18)
    - Adweek creative seminar, 1993 (Box 18)
    - AEF Ambassador speech, 1984 (Box 18)
    - Ameritech presentation, 1992 (Box 18)
    - Atlanta Broadcasting Executives Club (includes Robert Edens, "The Generation Gap is Money in the Bank"), 1970 (Box 18)
    - Bank Marketing Association, 1985 (Box 18)
    - Beef Council, 1981 (Box 18)
    - Canton Forum, 1997 (Box 18)
    - CASE (Council for Advancement and Support of Education), 1990 (Box 18)
    - Chicago Advertising in the 1980s, undated (Box 18)
    - Denver Advertising Federation, 1992 (Box 18)
    - Development of an Idea, 1969 (Box 18)
    - Difference Between British and American Advertising, undated (Box 18)
    - Donald Thompson--Advertising Trends in the 80s, 1983 (Box 18)
    - Donald Zuchert, undated (Box 18)
    - Eulogy for Allin Proudfoot, 1994 (Box 18)
    - Future of Advertising, 1994 (Box 18)
    - Houston outdoor speech, undated (Box 18)
    - Huffy Corporation presentation, 1993 (Box 18)
    - If I Were a Chief Institutional Officer..., undated (Box 18)
    - Indianapolis talk, circa 2003 (Box 18)
    - Jacques Seguela--Tomorrow Has a Future, 1996 (Box 18)
    - John Ferrell--Advertising in the Year 2000, 1989 (Box 18)
    - Life Among the Mad Men, undated (Box 18)
    - Management and Leadership in Times of Encroachment, undated (Box 18)
    - Marrakesh talk, 1992; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Martin Sorrell--Beans and Pearls, 1996 (Box 19)
    - MPA Kelly Awards, 1993 (Box 19)
    - New Business: Issues and Answers, 1979 (Box 19)
    - Out of Thin Air, 1999 (Box 19)
    - Pokagon, undated (Box 19)
    - Presentation for Easy Spirit Shoes, 1992 (Box 19)
    - RAMA (Retail Advertising and Marketing Association) meeting, 1994 (Box 19)
    - Ray College of Design, undated (Box 19)
    - Speech about education, undated (Box 19)
    - Uncle Ben's presentation, 1981 (Box 19)
    - VCMA annual meeting, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Wearing 24 Sheets in Chicago, undated (Box 19)
    - Why I Go to Cannes Every Year, undated (Box 19)
    - Young Executives Club, 1993 (Box 19)
  - Photographs, 1945-1997 and undated; 13
    - AAAA, undated (Box 19)
    - Air Force, 1958-1959 (Box 19)
    - Cannes, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Chicago Advertising Federation Awards, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Chicago Public Education Fund, 2006-2007 (Box OV2)
    - Childhood/Youth, 1940s-1950s (Box 19)
    - Denver Advertising Federation, 1992 (Box 19)
    - EURO RSCG France, undated (Box 19)
    - EURO RSCG Tatham, 1997 (Box OV2)
    - Executive Service Corps, undated (Box 19)
    - Ford--Pink Submarine Shoot, undated (Box 19)
    - Golf, 1993-1994 and undated (Box 19)
    - Group photos and others, undated, 4 folders (Box OV2)
    - Group photos and others, undated (Box 19)
    - Group photos and others, undated, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Harvard Advanced Management Program, 1982 (Box OV5)
    - JWT--Cancun seminar, undated (Box 20)
    - JWT celebration/Park West (Rydholm as Boy George), undated (Box 20)
    - JWT miscellaneous, 1970s-1980s (Box 20)
    - JWT--Schlitz shoot, undated (Box 20)
    - JWT--Schlitz shoot, undated (Box OV2)
    - JWT--Solo photos, undated (Box OV2)
    - Michael de Anda as Pancho Villa, undated (Box 20)
    - Northwestern University, Phi Delta Theta, 1956-1961 (Box OV2)
    - One Magnificent Mile (Chicago), 2000 (Box OV2)
    - Rydholm solo photos, undated (Box 20)
    - Rydholm with Hillary Clinton, undated (Box 20)
    - Tatham, undated (Box 20)
    - Young & Rubicam, 1961-1962 (Box OV5)
  - Slides, 1967-1996 and undated; 14
    - Ameritech, undated (Box 20)
    - Boy George, 1983-1984 (Box 20)
    - Chicago Sun Times, 1996 (Box 20)
    - Chicago Tribune, 1996 (Box 20)
    - Compacter, 1969 (Box 20)
    - Disney, 1975 (Box 20)
    - Eddie George and Elna, Uncle Ben's, Rice Follies, 1968 (Box 20)
    - EURO RSCG France, undated (Box 20)
    - European Naturals (Nowhere, Sub Ladies, Rain Barrel, Sandbox), 1970 (Box 20)
    - European Naturals (Nowhere), 1970 (Box 21)
    - Football commercial, undated (Box 21)
    - For Brunettes Only, 1970; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Fountain of Youth, 1985 (Box 21)
    - Fred Clark commercials, 1968; 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Harvard Advanced Management Program, 1982; 3 folders (Box 21)
    - JWT, 1970 (Box 21)
    - JWT Bermuda Creative Seminar, undated (Box 21)
    - JWT Cap Ferrat, 1980 (Box 21)
    - JWT--For Brunettes Only, 1970 (Box 21)
    - Kentucky Fried Chicken, 1968 (Box 21)
    - Kentucky Fried Chicken, 1968 (Box 22)
    - Kristin, Brund, Elvis, Art Fair Detroit, 1972 (Box 22)
    - Look of Nature shoot, 1972; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Messner, undated (Box 22)
    - Mighty Morsels, 1968 (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 22)
    - Schlitz, 1978 (Box 22)
    - Schlitz Jerry Reed shoot, 1978 (Box 22)
    - Schlitz, Mighty Morsels, 1968-1979 (Box 22)
    - Sears May Sale, Utah trip, 1969 (Box 22)
    - Sears, Texas, Detroit, Art Fair, 1969 (Box 22)
    - St. Croix V.I. submarine shoot, 1967 (Box 22)
    - Submarine, 1967 (Box 22)
    - USA Today, 1996 (Box 22)
    - Tatham Euro RSCG rum reel, undated (Box 22)
    - Tropic Freezer, undated (Box 22)
    - Wall Street Journal, 1996 (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted slides, undated (Box 23)
- Print Materials, 1958-2014 and undated; 2
  - 22nd Annual Andy Awards, 1986 (Box 24)
  - 37th Outdoor Advertising Competition, 1969 (Box 24)
  - AAAA--Agency vol. 8 no. 2, 1998 (Box 24)
  - AAAA--Impact of Advertising on Stock Performance, 1997 (Box 24)
  - AAAA In the News, 1997 (Box 24)
  - AAAA Roster and Organization 1999-2000 (Box 24)
  - AAAA--Why Advertise?, 1996 (Box 24)
  - AAAA--Your Brand Is Your Future, 1996 (Box 24)
  - ABA Annual Meeting, 2003 (Box 24)
  - ABA--Law and the Courts Vol. III: Juries, 2001 (Box 24)
  - Ad Age Creativity Special, 1996 (Box 24)
  - Adcrafter--Meeting of Minds, 1994 (Box 24)
  - American TV Commercials Festival, 1966 (Box 24)
  - Annabel's Member of the Year: Sir Darryl Hartley Leonard Esq., undated (Box 24)
  - BBDO Chicago Office profile, 1964 (Box OV10)
  - Bob Pile--Crisis Every 15 Minutes, 1988 (Box 24)
  - Bruce MacDonald--The Bridge (chapter by Rydholm), 2008 (Box 24)
  - Cannes Festival, 1988-1989 (Box 25)
  - CEBA (Creative Excellence in Business Advertising) Awards, 1997 (Box OV10)